<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Featured Projects on Outliers</title>
    <link>/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Featured Projects on Outliers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:27:21 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sounds of Mumbai</title>
      <link>/projects/som/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 03:46:22 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/som/</guid>
      <description>Sounds of Mumbai is unique because capturing the sense of being at a place is hard. We often associate a space with just its visuals, but in reality we experience it through all our senses. Tapan has managed to accomplish it beautifully, not just in Sounds of Mumbai but also in his other projects by combining his skills in tech and his love for travel. Through audio, micro interaction animations, videos and transitions, Tapan has created an immersive experience for project viewers to feel like they are part of a city’s culture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bharati</title>
      <link>/projects/bharati/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:42:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/bharati/</guid>
      <description>Major Indian languages lend themselves to natural unification due to their common phonetic structure but only differ in visual appearances. Our languages are arranged in a logical pattern by the 5th-century scholar Panini based on vibrations and sounds from the different parts of the mouth with the distinction of vowels and consonants in an orderly manner, unlike the English alphabets.
The only ambiguity lies in the mismatch of sounds and shapes of the fonts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indecoded</title>
      <link>/projects/indecoded/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:42:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/indecoded/</guid>
      <description>Indecoded presents a simple interface to explore data visualization via cartograms. On clicking any of 14 parameters like Literacy, GDP, HDI or GDP/Capita, the Indian map distorts to show the effect of the parameter on the individual states.
As the transformation is animated, one can observe the gradual change in data as transition happens between variables. The colors change according to the ranks. Blue indicates high index (high population, high literacy) and Red indicates low index (low population, low literacy).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kathabhidhana</title>
      <link>/projects/kathabhidhana/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:42:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/kathabhidhana/</guid>
      <description>In an age where technology is becoming so flexible that we can make sense out of languages on a mathematical level and use the structure to create meaningful applications, keeping languages agile and technology-compatible is a necessity.
What a shame that rich languages like Sanskrit have no smart way of learning like Duolingo or Memrise. It isn&amp;rsquo;t just language learning which is hampered because of lack of digitization but also a large section of our society cannot access to the wealth of information internet has to offer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shhh! Sex</title>
      <link>/projects/shhh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:42:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/shhh/</guid>
      <description>India&amp;rsquo;s inhibitions about discussing sex get surfaced when a condom ad appears on TV and everyone in the family pretends not to notice anything. Sex is an awkward topic, even for the most educated people in our country and that is not okay.
As a result of this reticence, kids don&amp;rsquo;t learn about sex from their parents but from porn, which creates an unhealthy, unrealistic impression of sex in their minds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Heritage Lab</title>
      <link>/projects/heritage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:42:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/heritage/</guid>
      <description>In the recent past, the world has seen a paradigm shift in the concept of what a museum is. Museums are no longer just edifices accommodating historical artefact displays but instead, they are living thriving celebration of culture, both historical and contemporary.
The situation in our nation, however, is abysmal. While other museums around the world are digitizing their collections and putting them online, most museums in India still lack a website or digital presence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual KGP</title>
      <link>/projects/vkgp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:42:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/vkgp/</guid>
      <description>Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be exciting to have your college reunion at the same canteen you used to hang out with your friends in the college days? Technology can enable us to capture and store spatial experiences today that can be revisited years later, even if that space might not be the same in real life.
Prateek Srivastava and Siddharth Jindal are undergrads from IIT Kharagpur who are working on a Virtual Reality experience at SAVR Lab, Dept of Industrial and System Engineering.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>