<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Web on Outliers</title>
    <link>/categories/web/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Web on Outliers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:42:51 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sounds of Mumbai</title>
      <link>/projects/som/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 03:46:22 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/som/</guid>
      <description>Sounds of Mumbai is unique because capturing the sense of being at a place is hard. We often associate a space with just its visuals, but in reality we experience it through all our senses. Tapan has managed to accomplish it beautifully, not just in Sounds of Mumbai but also in his other projects by combining his skills in tech and his love for travel. Through audio, micro interaction animations, videos and transitions, Tapan has created an immersive experience for project viewers to feel like they are part of a city’s culture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indecoded</title>
      <link>/projects/indecoded/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:42:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/indecoded/</guid>
      <description>Indecoded presents a simple interface to explore data visualization via cartograms. On clicking any of 14 parameters like Literacy, GDP, HDI or GDP/Capita, the Indian map distorts to show the effect of the parameter on the individual states.
As the transformation is animated, one can observe the gradual change in data as transition happens between variables. The colors change according to the ranks. Blue indicates high index (high population, high literacy) and Red indicates low index (low population, low literacy).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>